<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analytics Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://keisha-g.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Data Analytics Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 17:36:20 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://keisha-g.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Web Scraping (Twitter)</title>
      <link>https://keisha-g.github.io/posts/web-scraping-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keisha-g.github.io/posts/web-scraping-twitter/</guid>
      <description>For my honours project (for more details, check the &amp;lsquo;Projects&amp;rsquo; tab), I needed to build a program that would scrape Twitter/X for tweets. This was done using the snscrape library and Python. This project also had a front-end interface in order to give the program inputs instead of doing it through the CLI.&#xA;The program takes in the number of total tweets wanted and what hashtag you want the scraper to crawl through to collect them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Types and Attributes of Data Visulisations and When they should be Used</title>
      <link>https://keisha-g.github.io/posts/data-visulisations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keisha-g.github.io/posts/data-visulisations/</guid>
      <description>There are many different types of data visulisations. However, a skilled data analyst will use the most effective type of visulisation to visually aid the &amp;lsquo;storytelling&amp;rsquo; / what story the data shows. Not only do suitable data vcisulisations aid in this, but bad choices for data visulisations can mislead an audience to believing falsehoods or just confuse them.&#xA;The following graph is the standard &amp;lsquo;bad&amp;rsquo; visulisation - looking at the graph below, what do you immediately infer about gun deaths in Florida?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is Data Preprocessing?</title>
      <link>https://keisha-g.github.io/posts/data-preprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keisha-g.github.io/posts/data-preprocessing/</guid>
      <description>Data preprocessing is a crucial step in the data analysis pipeline that involves cleaning, transforming, and preparing raw data for analysis. It aims to improve the quality, consistency, and usability of the data by addressing issues such as missing values, outliers, inconsistencies, and formatting errors. Data preprocessing is essential for ensuring that the data is suitable for analysis and modeling tasks.&#xA;Data preprocessing is a crucial step in the data analysis pipeline that involves cleaning, transforming, and preparing raw data for analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bias in Machine Learning and AI</title>
      <link>https://keisha-g.github.io/posts/bias-in-machine-learning-and-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keisha-g.github.io/posts/bias-in-machine-learning-and-ai/</guid>
      <description>With the increasing amount of commercial use of machine learning (ML) systems, these systems&amp;rsquo; fairness and unbiased nature become an issue of vital importance. These systems are being employed to make decisions that are usually protected by anti-discrimination laws and, thus, unmonitored, are having an adverse effect on society. The interest in this field is not just one of social importance but also one of utility. A bias based unfairly on protected characteristics instead of other attributes would not result in the most efficient, &amp;lsquo;merit-based&amp;rsquo; outcome.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Honours Project</title>
      <link>https://keisha-g.github.io/projects/honoursproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 17:36:20 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keisha-g.github.io/projects/honoursproject/</guid>
      <description>I undertook my honours during my fourth year of university. In my research project, I wanted to experiment with different types of dataset collection and preprocessing methodologies and how they affected the performance of Topic models (a type of AI model).&#xA;The goal of a topic model is to summarise a long piece of text/s by examining the co-occurrence patterns of words and organising the words it sees into a &amp;rsquo;topic&#39;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Analytics Project: Annalysing Australian Trade 2023</title>
      <link>https://keisha-g.github.io/projects/dataanalytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 17:36:20 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://keisha-g.github.io/projects/dataanalytics/</guid>
      <description>The visulisations in this post are demonstrations of skills in excel and tableau (although tableau visulisations do not have interactivity as intended due to licensing issues).&#xA;Introduction This page is a report on data about Australian international trade. This report will highlight key information and trends on Australian international imports and exports with data that spans from 1988 - 2022. This report will also focus on the import &amp;amp; export main category of &amp;lsquo;0: food and live animals&amp;rsquo; for closer analysis.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
